That day, humanity remembered...
the terror of being ruled by them.
The humiliation of being kept in a cage.
Prepare for combat!
We have one target...
Defeat it, and make this humanity's
first base outside the walls.
Target approaching!
Split into five groups, just as we practiced!
We'll be the decoys!
Attack teams, switch to
Three-Dimensional Maneuver Gear!
We'll strike from all directions at once!
We'll show you the power
of humanity!
To You, 2,000 Years in the Future
The Fall of Zhiganshina (1)
Huh? Mikasa...
Let's head back.
What am I doing here?
You're so out of it.
Were you sound asleep?
No...
It's just, I feel like I had a really long dream.
What was it about?
I can't remember...
Eren, why are you crying?
The Year: 845 — Zhiganshina District
Listen!
These walls were constructed with God's wisdom!
They were given to us by God himself!
None may defile them!
Don't tell anyone that I was crying.
I won't...
But if you're crying for no reason,
why not have your dad check you over?
No way!
I can't tell my dad about it.
What are you crying over, Eren?
Hannes!
Did Mikasa get mad at you for something?
Why would that make me cry?
And you stink of alcohol!
Oh, come on...
You're all drinking again?
Why don't you join us?
Um, but don't you have work?
Yeah! We're guarding the gate today.
We spend all day here, so eventually,
we get hungry and thirsty.
And the fact that some of what
we drink may be alcohol...
Well, that isn't too big a problem.
Can you fight like that if you have to?
If we have to? When would we...
When else?!
If they breached the walls
and entered the city!
Ow...
Hey, Eren, don't yell like that...
The doctor's son is pretty lively today.
If they ever do breach
the walls, we'll do our jobs.
But that hasn't happened
for a hundred years.
But my dad says that you're in the most danger
when you lower your guard!
Doctor Jaeger, huh?
Well, he's right...
He once saved the whole city from an epidemic.
We owe him more than we could ever repay.
But that has nothing to do with them.
As a soldier, when you go up to repair the walls,
you can sometimes see them,
wandering around outside.
But this wall is fifty meters high.
They can't do anything about it.
Th-Then,
you're actually not prepared to fight them?
Nope.
What?!
Then stop calling yourselves the Garrison,
and become the Wall Repair Corps!
I wouldn't mind that...
But listen, Eren...
If we're fighting,
it means things are bad.
As long as everyone's laughing at us
and calling us useless freeloaders,
that means we're all safe.
Even if we can never leave
these walls for our entire lives,
as long as we eat and sleep, we'll survive...
But that makes us just like...
Just like cattle!
That's a brave kid you have there.
Not like he could do anything
about it, huh, Hannes?
Y-Yeah.
Hey, Eren!
Strange kid.
Does he want to join the Survey Corps?
Eren, you should stop considering the Survey Corps.
What? You're going to tell
me they're stupid, too?
That isn't it...
The Survey Corps is back!
The front gate's opening!
Let's go, Mikasa!
The heroes are back!
Damn it, I can't see!
These are all that made it back?
Everyone else must've been eaten.
That's what happens when
you go outside the walls.
Moses! Moses!
Um, my son, Moses... I don't see him.
Where is he?
This is Moses's mother.
Bring it.
That is all we managed to retrieve.
But my son...
He helped, right?
Even if he didn't do anything directly...
My son's death helped humanity
fight back, didn't it?!
Of course!
No.
Our recon this time didn't...
No,
we never...
Never learn a thing!
It's my fault...
My own incompetence killed our men!
And we still don't even know what they are!
What a mess...
You've got that right.
It's like our taxes all go to fatten them up.
What are you doing, stupid brat?
Hey!
What are you doing, Mikasa?!
Get back here!
Mikasa, you can let go now!
What was that for?
The firewood spilled everywhere!
Eren,
do you still want to join the Survey Corps?
Help me pick these up...
There isn't enough to bother.
Information We Can Share So Far:
About the Walls (1)
Humanity lives within three walls.
The outermost is Wall Maria.
The second, Wall Rose.
The innermost is Wall Sina.
Information We Can Share So Far:
About the Walls (2)
Distance between each is roughly the same.
100km separate Maria and Rose.
130km separate Rose and Sina.
From Sina to the center is about 250km.
Back.
Welcome home.
Oh, Eren!
You actually worked hard for a change.
Yeah...
What?
Your ears turned red.
That means you're lying.
Mikasa helped you, didn't she?
Huh? Are you going somewhere, Dad?
Work?
Yes, I'm going inland to see patients.
Probably for two or three days.
Eren said he wants to join the Survey Corps.
M-Mikasa, I told you not to tell them!
Eren!
What are you thinking?
Do you know how many people
have died outside the walls?
I do!
In that case...
Eren...
Why do you want to go outside?
I want to know what it's like out there.
I don't want to spend my life inside
the walls, not knowing anything!
Also...
If no one carries on their work,
all the casualties till now will have been in vain!
I see.
The ship is waiting.
I'll be going now.
Wait...
You need to talk to Eren!
Karla, human curiosity is not something
you can restrain with a lecture.
Eren...
When I get back,
I'll show you what I've kept secret
in the basement all this time.
R-Really?
Bye!
I won't let you.
Joining the Survey Corps?
Don't be stupid.
Huh? Stupid?!
I think people who're fine being cattle
are way more stupid!
Eren!
Mikasa,
sometimes he doesn't think things through.
When you're in trouble,
you must help one another.
Okay.
What's wrong, heretic?
If you don't like it, hit back!
No way.
That would put me on your level!
What?!
You know what I said is true.
That's why you're hitting me instead of arguing.
Doesn't that mean you admit I win?
Shut your damned mouth!
Stop it!
That's Eren!
The fool's back.
He wants to get his ass kicked?
Let's give him what he wants!
M-Mikasa's here, too!
N-No... Let's get out of here!
They ran away when they saw me!
No, they ran when they saw Mikasa.
Ouch...
Hey, are you okay, Armin?
I can stand on my own.
All right.
So I said that humanity should
go out into the world someday.
And they hit me and called me a heretic.
Damn it.
Why does everyone act like you're
crazy if you want to go outside?
Because staying within the walls has
brought peace for a hundred years.
They're afraid that if many of us
venture out, we'll risk letting them in.
So the royal government declared
any interest in the outside world taboo.
That's our lives we're risking,
so it's our business!
You can't.
No.
Come to think of it, why did you tell my parents?
I don't remember ever saying I'd help.
H-How did it go?
Well... They weren't happy.
I bet.
But you're right.
I wonder about those who think staying
inside the walls will protect us forever.
Mom!
Just because the walls haven't
been breached in a hundred years
doesn't mean they won't be
breached today...
What?
An explosion?
Over there!
I think something fell from the sky!
Hey, Armin!
What's wrong?
What can you see?
No way...
That wall
is fifty meters tall!
It's one of them...
A Titan!
It broke...
a hole in the wall...
They're coming inside!
The Titans are getting inside!
We have to get out of here!
Eren!
My house is over there...
My mom!
Mikasa!
It's all over...
The Titans are going
to take the city!
Nothing hit my house!
Once I turn that corner,
my house will still be there!
Mom!
Eren...
Mikasa, grab that side!
We have to get this off her!
Hurry, Mikasa!
I know.
The Titans are inside, aren't they?
Eren, take Mikasa and run!
Now!
I want to run!
So hurry and get out of there!
My legs were crushed by the rubble.
Even if I get out, I can't run.
You understand, don't you?
Then I'll carry you!
Why do you never listen to me?!
At least listen this one last time!
Mikasa!
No...
No!
If you don't go, all three of us will...
Hannes!
Take the children and run!
Don't underestimate me, Karla.
I'll defeat the Titan, and save you all!
Wait!
Don't try to fight it!
She's right.
If it were just the kids, I could save them.
But I'm going to repay that family
for what they've done for me!
Wait, Hannes!
What are you doing?!
Thank you.
My mom is still back there!
Eren! Mikasa!
You must survive!
Don't go...
Stop!
That day, humanity remembered...
the terror of being ruled by them.
The humiliation of being kept in a cage.
The Fall of Zhiganshina.
All humanity could do
was pray, scream, and die...
Among them, Eren was
the only one to swear revenge.
That Day
The Fall of Zhiganshina (2)
Illustration: Shuuzou Oshimi (The Flowers of Evil)